A Finding Aid to the Walter Horn Papers, 1908-1992, bulk 1943-1950, in the Archives of American Art AAA.hornwalt
Archives of American Art
- U. S. Army Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives Section Files, circa 1938-1989; Series 3; 0.6 Linear feet Box 2-4, OV 5-6
  - Art Looting Investigation and Interrogation Reports, 1945-1946; 3.4
    - Gold Treasure of Kremsmunster Report, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 73)
      Horn's original report to the U.S. Army.
    - Summary of Investigation of the Coin Collection, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      Original investigation report and copy along with 2 photostatic copies of a German document.
    - "A Trip to Ghetto Theresienstadt", circa 1946 (Box 2, Folder 75)
      Author of report unknown, possibly Colonel Charlie Ross. Ghetto Theresienstadt is a concentration camp.
    - "Das Schickel der Kulturgutbergung in den osterreichischen Salinen im Weltkrieg 1939-1945", circa 1946 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Printed Materials, circa 1938-1949; 1975-1983; 3.5
    There are news clippings and articles about World War II and the activities of the Monuments Men. Miscellaneous items include a German publication containing an article and numerous images of the Imperial Regalia or Crown Jewels and a poster commemorating the recovery of the Holy Hand of St. Stephen, a sacred relic from Hungary also known as The Holy Right.
    - Das Reichs Kleinodien, circa 1938 (Box 2, Folder 77)
      Oversized material housed in Box 4, Folder 8.
    - Commemorative Poster for the Return of the Holy Hand of St. Stephen, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      Oversized material housed in OV 5, Folder 5. The poster commemorates the return of The Holy Right or the Holy Hand of St. Stephen, a sacred relic which was looted by the Nazis along with the Crowl Jewels of Hungary (the Crown of St. Stephen, sceptre and orb).
    - Articles and News Clippings, circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Articles and News Clippings, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      Oversized material housed in OV 6, Folder 1.
    - Articles and News Clippings, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 81)
      Oversized material housed in OV 6, Folder 2.
    - Articles and News Clippings, 1949; 1975-1983 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      Oversize material housed in OV 6, Folder 3.
    - Oversized Publication and Images of the Crown Jewels of the Holy Roman Empire, circa 1938 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Oversized material from Box 2, Folder 77.
    - Oversized Commemorative Poster for the Return of the Holy Hand of St. Stephen, 1945 (Box OV 5, Folder 5)
      Oversized material from Box 2, Folder 78.
    - Oversized Newspaper, 1946 (Box OV 6, Folder 1)
      Oversized material from Box 2, Folder 80.
    - Oversized Articles and News Clippings, 1947-1948 (Box OV 6, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 2, Folder 81.
    - Oversized Articles and News Clippings, 1949; 1983 (Box OV 6, Folder 3)
      Oversized material from Box 2, Folder 82.
  - Photographs, 1945-1946; 3.6
    Found here are scattered photographs relating to art recovery.
    - Unidentified Soldiers with Box of Recovered Loot, circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Unidentified Couple, circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Helmuth and Edeltraut von Hummel, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Crown Jewels of Hungary, circa 1946 (Box 2, Folder 86)
      Photograph shows the Holy Crown of St. Stephen, the sceptre, and the orb which were stolen from Hungary.
- University of California, Berkeley Administrative Files, 1938-1976; Series 4; 0.1 Linear feet Box 3
  Miscellaneous files concerning Horn's job appointments, promotions, and salary while working at the University of California, Berkeley. Papers about the Loyalty Oath controversy at Berkeley and Horn's retirement speech are also included.
  - Lecturer Appointment, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Salary and Promotions, 1941-1976 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Loyalty Oath Articles, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Loyalty Oath Letters and Reports, bulk 1950; 1949-1951; 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Outline of Interdisciplinary Work, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Research Lecturer Position, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Horn's Retirement Speech along with Introduction by Leo Ettlinger, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Photographs, 1989; Series 5; 1 Folders Box 3
  There is one folder of color photographs taken by Horn showing his papers boxed in storage before everything was shipped to the Archives of American Art.
  - Horn's Papers Before Shipment to Archives, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)